Good afternoon. Welcome to the public
service committee meeting for March 16,
2026.
I'm going to try to do this from memory.
So, if you're in the audience and you
would like to come forward, please come
up to the podium, um, introduce
yourself, turn on the the microphone,
and share your thoughts with us. If you
have your phones with you, please shut
them off or set them to vibrate.
Um, this will be the only business that
we conduct today
and I think that's it. So with that, can
we have the first item, please? Number
13, ordinance, second reading, amending
the official zoning map of the city of
Cheyenne. Classification for land
located north of West College Drive and
east of South Parsley Boulevard from PUD
Harmony Valley planned unit development
to NR3 neighborhood residential high
density.
And do we have a staff report?
Hi, Matt.
Hi, Madam Chair. Uh, Morgan Dennis,
Planning and Development. Uh, this is a
zone change request for lot one, block
one, Harmony Valley,
fourth filing from Harmony Valley PUD to
NR3.
Uh the zone districts that surround this
parcel of land are MR to the north, P
the Harmony Valley PUB to the east,
county light industrial to the west, and
county land use to the south. That uh
land use is mainly single family
residentials.
The future land use map designates this
area as mixeduse commercial. This
designation supports more commercial or
live work developments. um that could be
activity centers. Residential is
typically secondary in this designation
and should be highdensity developments.
Uh this site is also located at the
intersection of South Parsley and West
College Drive. Uh traffic from these
streets could be higher than desired in
a residential area.
The existing zoning of Harmony Valley
PUD outlines this area as highdensity
residential. This designation allows for
intense residential development and
commercial development that is normally
allowed in the CB zone. Um and then the
proposed zone doesn't allow any uh
commercial development.
Uh the NR3 district is intended for the
high density urban residential
um developments. um application of this
use near planned activity
centers or concentration of density
without walking access or non to
non-residential uses and quality urban
amenities should be avoided um due to
the topography and current development
patterns of the area. There are no truly
walkable destinations at this time.
The more optimal zone for this area is
the MUB mixeduse business zone. This
zone accomplishes the future land use
map objectives as it allows for
commercial and highdensity residential
development. This corridor lacks
commercial zoning as there is a lot of
residential development in the area. MUB
is the combination of the NR3 and the MB
zone which allows for NR3 lot types and
residential design standards. The
comprehensive plan does support
flexibility to adjust to market demands
and supports the development of housing
to meet to meet demands.
While the NR3 will limit overall
allowable development action within the
area, adding housing units will be
meeting market and development demands.
On March 2nd, the planning commission
heard this case and recommends approval
for the zone change. I stand for
questions.
>> Thank you, Morgan. Dr. Aldridge. Uh,
Chairwoman Emmens through you. In
looking at this and being very familiar
with this topography
>> um in that area, I noticed that there's
been being a lot of work dirt work done
right now. Yes.
>> Because that's a pretty substantial drop
from Parsley Boulevard to the bottom of
this property.
>> Um, I'm wondering how many um
apartments or dwellings we're looking at
or units in that area. Um, and I'm
reading from reading this, I'm guessing
that it's going to be a larger complex
versus like the fourplexes that are just
to the east of that.
Yeah. Um, I will madam chair through you
uh to Dr. Aldridge. I am going to refer
to the developer for that question. He
is going to have the more comprehensive.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Any other questions for Morgan?
>> Just I had one. Have we heard from
anyone
Emmens um on any um comments from the
surrounding neighbors or the public on
this change?
>> Um no, there has been no public comment
regarding this one.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, we're going to go to public
comment now.
>> Good afternoon. John Sers,
representative of True Great Land
Development for this project. If I may,
we're gonna answer Dr. Aldred's
questions. Pretty simple.
>> Thank you.
>> If I may, uh, the plan before you is a
site plan that has previously been
submitted through the city. We are
through the correction process at this
point. We resubmitted this literally
last week on Thursday so we can finish
up our comment period so we can have
this completed at this time period and
working with staff u we've been going
through as you'll see in the next two
items changing stuff out of the PUB
zoning back into the NR3 which meets the
high desensity regionally
thought we were going to do over there
versus the commercial application
pulling the cars off is not what we have
any interest in doing at this time
period. So the plan is and then we're
not hiding anything that has already
been submitted. This is third round of
comments at this point and we should be
wrapping that up with working with BOP
on a waterline and comments from city
staff. In working through this, we we
recognize we probably needed to get this
over to NR3 based on the highdensity
residential. So we are not putting in
the forplexes to carry that through. Um
and I'm here to answer any questions I
may have not touched on.
Hey, do we have questions for the
developer? Dr. Aldridge. Uh, chairwoman
for you. So, how many units? It looks
like it's there's a 24plex apartment and
three stories high and it looks like
there are five of those. Is that
>> Madam Chair through you? Yes, there is
five 24 units apartment complex going
in.
>> Followup question. Go ahead.
>> Um, and the parking is all exterior
external. There's not any under um not
um
>> underground
>> not necessarily underground but you know
the main floor isn't necessarily parking
than with three stories on top.
>> Madam chair through you at this
particular site we don't the the
potential buyer has no interest for that
at this time period as other locations
will be coming forward with here in the
next couple of months. We do have
buildings that have the parking going
underneath. On this particular plan,
you'll notice that there is designated
garage spaces along the north for uh
people to go ahead and want to purchase
that additionally or rent those
additionally. Um but yes, we are trying
to keep the uh parking on the outside
and not enclosed at this time period.
>> Good. And it looks like there's only 15
of those parking garages that are going
to be available to these um whatever it
is
125 apartments.
>> Madam Chair, through you. Yes. at this
time. Um we looked at trying to put more
of the garage spaces in, but then you're
also realistically unless somebody has a
prize collection of a car or something.
Um they're going to be storage container
situations and we feel that the
surrounding community already has some
stoages being placed and built at this
time period. They could go ahead and put
that at that location.
>> Thank you.
Any other questions for the developer?
Mr. Leborn. Thank you, Madam Chairman.
So, I see there's a
storm sewer line evidently coming in
from the north and going to a detention
facility there towards Parsley. Is that
right?
A broken line.
>> Go ahead.
>> I didn't know if Madam Chair through
you. I didn't know if you wanted to
continue, Pete. So, we were That's why I
was pausing there for a second. Yes. So,
we actually worked with the city to
collect water uh up on top in the
Harmony Meadows subdivision previously a
year or two ago. That was completed last
year. That water is collected, comes
down through a series of pipes and
actually goes to the detention pond
that's next to Parsley at that point.
From that, that naturally releases and
heads down to Allison. One of the things
that we have incorporated is that
working with city staff is to go ahead
and as you know with our own park that
we've built over there. We've gone ahead
and actually collecting as much water as
we can to use for the recycling in that
area so we can water the field and
everything else and recycle that water.
So we have diverted some of that water
to go down to the pond to actually go
ahead and collect and move over there.
So you'll notice there's two catch
basins on Richard Martin almost at the
corner of Richard Martin and LCG. We
have diverted what is coming in on the
parking lot side to collect over at that
and that pipes actually goes all the way
down to the existing park that we have
down there and our pump house will come
online this summer and we will be using
the recycled water to go ahead and
irrigate all the uh parkland over in
that area.
>> Thank you. I I'd like to learn more
about that. That's a interesting uh step
forward that I haven't seen before. But
uh I was also wondering about
connectivity to the neighborhood up
above considering that slope.
Madam Chair, through you if I may. So
Pete, working through all this at this
time period. Unfortunately, there's a
portion of the hill at south that we are
working on uh lowering down that hill as
we continue through Harmony Valley fifth
filing that you previously approved. I
have a the next zone change will be
Harmony Valley 23rd filing. That's how
many filings we've done since the fifth
filing, which is the extension of Fifth
going over to Grand Harmony Boulevard.
Um, unfortunately, we can't get that
water all the way back over to the pond,
but is this pond adjacent to? So, we
will be working to try to manipulate
some of that water back over to the pond
to actually continue that. Furthermore,
I will let you know we have already had
a well permit in that area. So when and
if the well or the water's low for our
own irrigation purposes for the field
and all the green space over at that
point, we can fire up through our pump
house that's already on site with
bathrooms and so forth. On the backside,
we have an integrated a pump that goes
down to the pond, pulls water. We also
have a well that should we need to turn
it on to keep the pond full when we've
been dry like we are at this present
moment that we can supply water down to
the pond. So, we are trying everything
with not using city water to the best
available resource and recycling every
bit of the water on site to get it back
up and and irrigate the neighborhood and
the HOA.
>> Well, that's great. And but I was
wondering about access
from Harmony Valley up into the existing
neighborhood. I mean like a path or some
pedestrian access. Madam Chair, through
you Pete, if you'll recall when we were
doing the Harmony Valley Fifth Filing,
and I'll show you on the uh 23rd exhibit
here in a few, we have green space that
actually gets you up to there. City
staff is already currently working on
the York extension up to Cribbon that's
supposed to be released for funding in
2028. So York will continue up along
south and curl up. When you see the
plan, it'll come before you. And
granted, the final plat for the 23rd
just went in. We're actually working on
uh Grand Harmony going all the way up to
Allison as well as pathways to get up to
the school district. So, we are working
on reducing the slope on the hill so we
can get as many people to go up so
they're not trespassing on our property
and potential danger for us.
>> Thank you. Um,
maybe I could uh review this further
with you
at some other time, but I I do uh
uh recognize
there are some steps here that are a
little better than some things we've
seen. Okay.
>> Thank you, Mr. Ser.
>> Thank you.
>> Is is there any other public comment?
Okay. Okay. Hearing no other public
comment,
what is your preference, committee?
>> I would move to adopt on second reading.
>> Second.
>> Okay. Um, Dr. Aldridge moves to adopt
and uh, Councilman Lebornne second. All
in favor, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> And those opposed.
>> Okay. So, this will uh, the
recommendation for Monday night will be
to approve.
Next item,
>> number 14, ordinance, second reading,
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne, changing the zoning
classification for land located south of
West Allison Road, west of Walters
Boulevard and north of Grand Harmony
Boulevard from PUD Harmony Valley
Planned Unit development to NR3
neighborhood residential highdensity.
Staff report, please.
>> Oh, Morgan Dennis, Planning and
Development. Um this is a zone change
request for lot 2 block 10 Harmony first
filing from Harmony Valley PUB to NR3.
Uh zoning surrounding zoning for this
area is public and AG to the north,
Harmony
Meadows PUB to the east, mixeduse
business to the south, and public and an
ex
and an existing NR3 zone to the west.
The AG zone to the north is undergoing a
zone change as well. The future land use
map designates this area as urban
residential with a small portion in the
south being designated as mixeduse
residential. Both designations promote
highdensity residential developments.
This zone change would be an extension
of the existing NR3 to the west. The
current designation of this parcel
within the Harmony Valley PUD is medium
density residential which has similar
uses to the NR3 zone.
This parcel is between a school and an
existing neighborhood. While there is no
activity centers nearby, there is
non-residential development along
College Drive and there is an existing
pedestrian network in the area. There
was public comment made at the planning
commission by neighboring property
owners. their primary concern was about
the amount of traffic um that would be
generated with a potential development
at this location.
Um staff informed that traffic is not a
major consideration at a zone change. Um
however, when a PL for this parcel is
submitted for review, a traffic
worksheet or study will be submitted at
that time. The planning commission heard
this case and recommends for approval of
the zone change. And I stand for
questions.
Thank you. Questions for Miss Janis.
Dr. Aldridge.
>> Uh Chairwoman Imanster. You in looking
at this um map that's been provided for
us, it looks like um the Harmony Drive
or Harmony Boulevard. I can't remember
what it's called. at the corner there
where uh where Triumph sits and on
College
um in that big blue square that's public
um and that you can see Grand Harmony
kind of
makes an S around that
>> um up to Center Drive. Are we looking at
that Grand Harmony then going to uh work
its way completely through that
subdivision and this new area to West
Allison Road?
>> I will defer um Madam Chair through you.
Um I will defer to the developer for
that question.
>> I had one other question. One uh
follow-up question is uh that I had is
have we had any conversations with the
school district about going right up to
their property line?
Once again, I'll defer to the developer
about those questions.
>> Okay. Any other questions for Miss
Dennis?
>> All righty. Thank you,
>> Madam Chairwoman. Dr. Renie did join us
via audio, so that's what you're
hearing. So, he's on the meeting now.
>> Thank you. All right. Public comment.
John,
>> John Sers, agent for True Great Land
Development. I'm gonna give you a copy
of the uh map that I think Dr. Aldridge
was already looking for, but I was
already
if I may. So, in regards to this, this
was a continuation zoning that was
previously done on Harmony Valley Fifth
Filing. We did come in and ask for the
PUD to be modified to go to the NR3
zoning to allow the cottage lots that we
are proposing and actually getting going
here shortly. With that said, we wanted
to extend and we had always agreed to
that Harmony Valley Fifth Filing would
continue to the east over to Harmony
Meadows, I believe is the subdivision
there, and parallel that particular
subdivision. We will not have any direct
access with Grand Harmony Boulevard from
College all the way up to Allison going
into uh the Harmony Meadows existing
subdivision because they only have two
points of ingress egress. The Melody
loop or lane portion that shows off of
the Harmony Meadows due to topography
does not allow us to get a road through
there. We are working with city staff to
go ahead and get a pathway to get us
connected for those individuals to come
through. The first page I gave you was
the preliminary plat showing all the
green space that we have incorporated
that the HOA will maintain and not the
city. And then secondly, the plat that
was submitted last week as well. So both
items were pushed in on an expedited
that I will get to spend more time with
you in the coming weeks and months. Um
again, we are asking for the NR3 zoning
all the way through the area. That gets
us all the way up to the top and that
will put us at 308 residential units
over in that area for affordable housing
with the comment for the school
district. We've been working with the
school district and we are adjacent
property owners to the school district.
So, we have had to work with them on
that. Um, we hoped last week, but due to
weather conditions, we did not. Uh, we
are going to start carving down the hill
even more. So, it looks similar to what
is on the far west side when we started
dirt work this last summer. Um, so we
got the equipment showed up last week
and we were going to start on that and
thank goodness we didn't because as you
all know there was enough dust in the
air that we didn't need any extra at
that point. So, um, we have been working
with them. I've also been working with
city staff, especially engineering, um,
due to the potential failure of the
school district's pond up at the top
side. So, we are trying to coordinate
that and work with them even more so to
figure out how we can help, but work
together to figure out that because that
pond is not in the greatest condition.
And I hope that answers questions and
I'm willing to stand for more.
>> Questions for the developer.
>> Yes. Yes. Dr. Question, Dr. Emmens. So,
as you I look at this map, I see some
lots that are marked as being 28 feet
wide, like for instance, lot 8 um on
Danny at the corner of Danny Place and
um
Grand Harmony Boulevard.
Is that And then it's 57 feet from front
to back it looks like. Is that structure
going to face that 28 foot wide space or
is that will that structure be turned so
that it faces Grand Harmony versus Danny
Place?
>> Go ahead,
>> Madam Chair through you. So that's a
great question and I can touch it this
way. When you're looking at that, you'll
see only a straight line dimension.
You'll also see the curve. So as we've
done before, our lots are going to be
for the twin home product that we
produce is 30 feet wide by 97 feet deep.
the uh single family attached. That's a
different model for us that we had
really good uh luck with last summer
over on LCG. We are actually attaching
those at the garage this foregoing
period with two other units. And with
that said, those are 41 12 ft wide lots
by 97. Any and staff has made sure I
understand this completely.
The alley load has to have the cars
enter off the alley. The front door
either opens up to an existing or
proposed street as we've shown and or
common space. We cannot open up a front
door to the alley. So that is why you
see those situations. So no front door
should be opening up to anything other
than the designated street or open space
with the alley being the indicator for
where the garages are actually located.
So you won't see garages.
>> Question. Go ahead. So all of these will
have rear loaded garages. um chairwoman
administer and have we talked with our
um public works folks because I know
they're trying to move all the trash
cans to the front for um pickup. So, and
we'll who will be maintaining these
alleys um in the as the future moves
forward. Go ahead, Mr. Sers.
>> Thank you, Madam Chairman. So, a couple
of things I'm going to touch on real
quick. Yes, we've been working on Yes,
all of a sudden we wanted trash cans out
of the alley, but because these are
situated in the subdivision, there's two
parts to your question. We have worked
with city staff that we can request that
these lots actually go back into rear
load for all maintenance of picking up
trash. Second part to that, the alleys
currently are dedicated on the plat as
being shown that way. In working with uh
city engineering department on the fifth
filing,
we have to mandate or determine what the
thickness is of asphalt or concrete in
the alley sections. We currently have
geotech scheduled for roughly next week
to come up and do some borings on that.
If we go with asphalt, then the HOA will
have to maintain the alleyways. If it is
concrete then we have to allow the city
city will accept the alleys. I hope that
answers your question but that is the
fine line at this point on this
particular situation.
>> Followup question. Okay woman. So um one
follow-up question I have is uh true
grit as a developer
correct has how many HOAs currently and
um in projects that you've done and how
many uh HOAs are still functioning?
Madam Chair, through you. So, True Grit
is the only one on this particular
project which encompasses all of the
Harmony Valley subdivision. So, every
owner is actually chipping in a minimal
fee to maintain the open space areas for
the park. So, unfortunately, we're the
lucky ones that pay a city fee for
parks, but we actually have our own
parks and Noah parks in the area,
surrounding area. So, every one of those
residents is paying for the park that we
will put grass down this summer because
we missed the window, but we will
actually have the park. We're ready to
fire up the pump here shortly. So, we
are the only HOA for that and it is one
HOA for the whole entire Harmony Valley
subdivision.
>> Thank you.
Other questions for the developer,
Mr. Leborn?
>> Thank you. Um, could you get a little
deeper into the problems with the school
district pond?
Madam chair, through you, we know that
if you even look at the the uh
topography on the preliminary plat on
the first sheet I gave you, you'll see
where up in the northeast corner of
that, you're starting to see a route
that's being funneled with water. Um,
city staff has made that a concern of
theirs as well. Uh, it's a concern of
ours because if school district doesn't
address it, they're going to have a heck
of a problem should that fail. So in
being good neighbors we are working on
that. Can I speak to the particulars?
Not at this time. Sorry sir.
>> So
can you get into the effort to help
them? I mean moving that water
uh down the hill um pipe
easement. What?
>> Madam chair through you. You know I'm
going to tiptoe on this one so I don't
get myself in trouble here. But real
quick and easy, we have looked at you
have property being the city of Cheyenne
across the street in a low spot.
>> Across which street?
>> Allison.
>> So we are looking at a possibility of
whether or not we would take water from
how those ponds kind of come together
and networking them and getting it
across to City Street on the other side.
Otherwise, there's going to have to be a
requirement somehow uh for them to go in
and maintain andor
repurpose the pond correctly is the best
way I can touch that.
>> Thank you.
>> Other questions for the developer?
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Any other public comments,
Dr. um Oh, do we have any on online?
Okay.
So committee, I'm going to close the uh
public comment.
>> I would move to approve on second
reading.
>> Second.
>> Okay. Dr. um Aldridge has moved and uh
Councilman Lebornne seconded. All those
in favor, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed?
>> Okay. So the recommendation on Monday
night will be to approve on second
reading
>> number 15 ordinance second reading
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne changing the zoning
classification for land located north of
Allison Road and west of Waltershy
Boulevard from AG agricultural to NR3
neighborhood residential high density
>> staff report please.
>> Morgan Dennis planning and development.
Um, this is a zone change for a parcel
located northwest of the intersection of
West Allison Road and Walter from AG to
NR3. Surrounding zoning for this parcel
is county A1 to the north, Harmony
Valley and Harmony Meadows PUB to the
south, county or urban residential low
density um to the east, and public and
MR to the west. Um, the Harmony Val
Valley PUB parcel to the south is
currently undergoing a zone change to
NR3. If that was to be approved, the NR3
would not be isolated in this area.
Future land use map designates this
property as mixeduse commercial.
Residential developments are secondary
with within this designation.
Um, this lot is located at the
intersection of West Allison and Walter
Shide. to hight traffic streets. This
results in a higher volume of traffic
than might be desired for a residential
area. The optimal zone for this area is
the MUB mixed business zone. Based on
policies and future land use map, um it
would it would just work out better. Um
the intersection is currently lacking
commercial zoning. This parcel is not
located near any activity center, but
has commercial developments to the east
and schools nearby. pedestrian amenities
in are included in the area such as the
greenway.
The comprehensive plan does support
flexibility to adjust to market demands
while the NR3 will limit overall
development action in the area. Adding
housing units will meet a current
demand. Planning commission heard this
case and recommends approval for the
zone change. And I Oh, there's been no
public comment regarding this project
and I stand for questions. Okay,
questions for Miss Dennis.
>> Yes, ma'am.
>> Go ahead, Dr. Aldridge.
>> Uh, Chairwoman for you. As I'm looking
at this, it appears to me that this
property
might border
um a parcel that we had uh has had much
public input um to the north of it. Is
that accurate?
>> Yeah, sure. Madam chair through uh yes
yes I'm being
>> and if I remember correctly chairwoman I
emu
this also has
um one a very strange topography um that
some challenging topography I think in
this area for sure but also uh extremely
large power lines that run um either
alongside of it or through it. Is that
correct as well? I don't see them
indicated on this map. uh they are not
indicated on the plat on this map. Um
but to the north is a utility station
that is being used. So yeah, there are
quite a few power lines in the area.
>> Okay. Is
the sorry through you chairwoman. Is the
power station or power lines are there
are they between this property and what
has been referred to in our last
annexation as parcel 4?
Is it is it a corridor? I'm trying to uh
I'm I'm not as gonna talk about that
evidently. Okay.
>> Yeah. I'm not as familiar with the uh
Madam Chair. Yeah. I'm not as familiar
with the area. Um but I will allow
someone else who is Thank you.
>> talk on that.
>> Any other questions for staff?
>> Okay.
Um, so then we're going to go ahead for
public comment.
John Sers, agent for True Great Land
Development, substations to the north of
us on the north property line. The
substation carries up to the south line
of your late night last Monday night.
Fair enough.
I would also like to clarify we have
nothing to do with that annexation or
any other things. So, I just need to put
that on record based on what happened
Monday night. Um, with that said,
previously we came in uh tried to do a
work camp and was shut down on that
based on the current code. So, it did
fit, but how it worked. Um, we've not
touched this, but we do have uh much
interest in the area on looking at
housing for this particular piece of
land. So in an effort to move anything
along, so said
uh entities come into town as we are
experiencing, we are just trying to get
it in the proper zoning for for housing.
At this particular point, we have no
plans at this point. It's why I'm not
able to provide you anything at this
point. WAPA does run parallel to Grand
Harmony Boulevard from the south all the
way at College and even all the way down
to Meta all the way straight through on
a straight line. So, there is a there is
a WA power easement that just runs to
the north on this particular property
that goes into the substation. To make
sure we're clear and let you know on
that, um, we didn't show the easement
because on its own change is typically
not necessary.
Once and if we get the approval on this,
then we would look at what we may choose
to do on this particular property. But
as it sits, we can't do much of the
housing idea without getting this. And
this is the first component piece to
moving forward. Um, and so based on the
NR3 moving up, we would continue up the
hill.
Is an issue. That's why we actually have
looked at a couple of different ideas
should we need to, but you'd probably
have a terracing situation coming down
the hill. Um, whether that's housing,
multif family or something. Don't know
at this particular point. Don't want to
say anything further honestly, but we do
not know, but we have different ideas to
make that work.
Other questions for the developer?
>> Yes, ma'am. Go ahead.
>> Uh, Chairwoman,
so with this being changed to um what's
being recommended is NR3, correct? Um,
I'm assuming that whatever that would be
would increase the traffic pretty
dramatically in this area, which is a
concern with the West Allison feeding
into the junior high and the high school
there and younger drivers um, which are
always a challenge. And then, um, also
the Waltershide traffic from the
Sundance, they call Sundance apartments
across the street. And that has really
become more of a thorough affair now
with the Boys and Girls Club and Head
Start and the proposed rec center that
will be further to the uh east of that.
I'm just wondering as this moves
forward, and this may be a question for
our um city engineer or our planning
department,
the increased traffic as well as um
increased pedestrian traffic, I'm
assuming, will that trigger the need
then for traffic changes on Waltershide
and West Allison along with um sidewalks
and curb and gutter and all of those
good things.
Mr. Sers, Madam
>> Chair, for you. So, in in regards to
that, that came up last week. It was
interesting in regards to the previous
zone change that you were discussing.
Everybody was complaining about that.
Um,
uh, Erin Gates from uh, engineering was
here. She spoke during the public or
planning commission. Uh, Allison is
actually a minor collector already
and Walter Shid's designation is up in
that category as well. um due to the
narrowing of Waltershide at this present
time period and I know there is works
for that to get widened out and increase
you already pre you already have a
traffic light situation existing there.
Um as one of the uh people that spoke
about at the planning commission in
regards to the Harmony Valley 23rd area
um they complained about the stopway. I
said you and me both because people
don't in this town understand how a
four-way stop works and two people can
go at the same time. So, it goes all the
way down to I think um Tom's here, but I
believe Fifth Street and the bridge at
Fifth Street and going all the way to
the to the south on College is in the
works is what I had understood, but that
would rectify some of that as well.
>> Just one follow-up question, uh
Chairwoman,
having been at Triumph when they opened.
Originally, there was a roundabout
planned on Grand Harmony Boulevard,
which was a disaster planning um because
it literally was where the parking lot
emptied out onto Grand Harmony
Boulevard. And um so I'm just wondering
if there are any roundabouts planned for
this uh stretch from that would be from
Fox Farm to College. At this point,
>> I'm going to defer that to your city st
madam chair through you. I apologize. I
would defer that through your city staff
because that's outside of our spectrum
of our project. That's fair.
>> Okay. Any other questions for the
developer?
>> All right. Uh Mr. Cobb,
>> Madame Chair, uh Tom Cobb, city
engineer, just to answer Dr. Aldridge's
question through you. Um we do have a
roundabout planned at Fox Farm and
Walters. Um, right now I've got it
scheduled for 2028.
>> Go ahead.
>> Ask a question. As a followup, uh,
Councilwoman,
will that require the widening then
because Walters does narrow as you get
closer to College right now or maybe it
widens. Anyway, there's a difference in
width from far Fox Farm to College
Drive. Will that then standardize the
width of Waltershide from Fox Farm to
college?
>> Madam Chair, through you to Dr.
Aldridge. So this is a careful balance
right now. I guess I'm going to tell you
it's going to depend on the money that I
have available at that time. Um and I
don't know right now I have it planned
going down to the the road just I'm just
trying at Jefferson is I'm just going to
go to Jefferson to Fox Farm right now
with the with the money I have
available. That's what I projected,
ma'am.
>> Thank you.
Okay.
Any other public comment?
Okay. Members of the committee, do you
have any comments?
Dr. Renie.
Okay.
>> No, Madam Chair. Chairman, I do not.
>> I would move to approve on second
reading.
>> Second.
>> Okay. Dr. Aldridge moves to approve. And
uh Councilman Lebornne seconded. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> And those opposed. Okay. The
recommendation on Monday night will be
to approve on second reading.
Number 16, Ordinance, second reading,
amending the official zoning and
changing the zoning classification for
land located northwest of the
intersection of East 29th Street and
Central Avenue from MR medium density
residential to NR2 neighborhood
residential medium density.
>> Staff report.
>> Madam Chair, members of the committee,
Conor Planning and Development
Department. The zone change before you
is from MR medium density residential to
NR2 which is neighborhood residential uh
medium density. This is for a lot that
is already developed. Um right now there
is basically this lot would be
considered multif family. Um it's built
in a townhouse style. So what that means
is basically each unit um is just side
by side has its own front door. Um,
but what they're looking to do with this
is they would like to basically put each
of those units on their own individual
lot. So, this is only step one um of the
of this application. There will be a
plat that will be coming before you. It
should be on next week's agenda for
introduction. Um, but the zone change
has to go through before we can actually
approve that plat. So, that's why you're
seeing the zone change first. Um the
reason for the NR2 is to allow cottage
lots as a use by right. Um in the MR
zone they would have to go for a
conditional use before they could get
the plat approved. Uh but they feel that
they'd uh prefer to have the zone
changed to NR2. Much of the area is
residential um in nature and already
developed.
most of the area is also developed kind
of similar to the NR2 where you do have
rear loaded uh access.
So with this project um basically what
they're looking to do is zone it at NR2
so that they can then plat the property
so that each of the units are on their
own individual lot with a common open
space uh that would then be maintained
by an HOA. This would allow basically
each unit to be sold off individually
rather than it be considered one parcel
in a multif family building.
So that is why they are looking for the
NR2. Uh planning commission did hear the
zone change at their meeting on March
2nd and did recommend approval. I am
available for any questions.
>> Okay, questions for Mr. White.
>> Councilwoman through you. Um, I just
want to make sure I understand these are
so I believe these are the town homes
that are on central north of the old uh
public library. And so we're those homes
would remain. We're just changing the
zoning or the plat so that they would be
able to be sold individually as
single family dwellings even though they
are attached.
>> Madam Chair, through you to Dr. Aldrich.
Yes. So what this is looking at doing,
so right now uh it's one property owned
by a single person. Uh they basically
rent out each unit to individuals. Um
so what they're looking to do is they
would like to get it reszoned and then
plat it so that now each unit can
technically be sold off individually
rather than just rented. So they would
become single family attached. they
become true town houses uh rather than
being considered by zoning code as
multif family because it's only on one
parcel. Um that's why I mentioned they
they were built in a townhouse style. Um
I guess you can kind of think of this as
similar to
if you know the buildings up off of
Hines Boulevard right at uh kind of the
on-ramp. Um there's the north building
which is still considered multif family.
It's not subdivided or anything, but
then you have the south one which is all
condoed. That's basically what this is
looking to do, but not condo them. It's
looking at actually platting it so that
they're individual lots.
One follow-up question, chairwoman, you
when uh an owner does something like
this. Um because I know that probably
since these were built, and I'm guessing
that these were built maybe in the 80s,
early 90s. Um I'm trying to remember
when they were built. Is it longer than
that? Okay. Um, do they I'm guessing the
code has changed and so is the developer
or the owner going to have to bring
these up to code before they can sell
them as individual units? Um, and I'm
guess I'm wondering about for instance
firewall um and how many units you can
have attached before you have to have
that uh stop firewall.
Madam Chair, through you with this
project and I guess the applicant might
be able to comment more on this, but we
did have a pre-application meeting where
a building official and fire department
did ask those questions of what is
currently existing. My understanding is
they all have firewalls between each
unit already um and were built that way
even back in the day. So, my
understanding with this and from our
chief building official from that
meeting is that they would not have to
up update anything um at this time. Um
but I think for this to move forward, I
think they had to provide us something
that showed that it was it had some sort
of firewall between the units because
now you're putting a lot line. But
again, these were all built as multif
family side by sides where they probably
had to have some sort of fire rating
even back in the day cuz they were built
in that townhouse style. Um, but I can I
can let the um applicant
um provide more information on that if
they have that information.
>> Thank you. Okay, any other questions for
Seth?
Okay, then let's open it up for public
comment.
>> Yeah. chairman, committee members, Brad
Emmens, AVI, agent for the applicant. Uh
Connor did cover most of the stuff very
well. Um we did do with the
pre-application meeting with fire, they
did tell us what uh needed to be done
and provided. Um that has been done. The
reports are in the file um from the
architect or engineer that went up in
the attics, checked it, checked all the
stuff, checked it on the main floor. So
those reports are included in the uh
submitt
and um and in the end the real
difference here is for financing. Um if
you want to get down to the the end of
it, the these buildings could be condoed
ju just the same way. A condo u has to
first of all they can only do a 20-year
amortization on a condo. It's only a
5-year fixed um program. um the
advantage if you have a lot line and can
sell uh individual parcels, you can get
a regular WCDA mortgage. So, it's a
30-year fixed. So, really in the end, it
helps the purchaser more than than
anything. Um so, that's the primary
reason. If if it didn't go forward, it
would probably just be condoed and and
sold that way. Um, so I I do think it's
better for the future buyer as well as
um going through all of these extra I
shouldn't say extra steps but the steps.
Uh it does let the buyer know that what
kind of buildings how they were rated,
how they were built. Um there are some
things that um I believe um there is the
city has adopted the existing building
code. So there are items that are
meeting the existing building code as
well as the firewall code. So I don't
want to say if you built them exactly
the same today, they'd have to go under
the IRC. They wouldn't go through the
existing building code. So there would
be some differences if it was built
today, but it meets the townhouse
requirements, the fire requirements, and
the stuff in the existing building code.
So be happy to answer any other
questions.
>> Mr. Just out of curiosity, how far back
was the day?
>> I want to say there cuz we they actually
have the building plans which was
amazing. That's the thing you usually
don't have. I want to say it was um in
the 70s sometime. So
>> those are good days.
>> I could have that at the next public
service meeting. I'll I can pull that
information.
>> Yeah.
>> Any other questions for the developer?
Hey, thank you.
Hey, committee. Oh, is there any other
public comment?
Okay, so committee,
>> I would move to approve on second
reading.
>> Second.
>> Okay, Dr. Aldridge moves and Councilman
Leborn seconded. All those in favor,
please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> And those opposed. Okay. Okay. So, the
recommendation for Monday night will be
to approve on second reading.
>> Number 17, ordinance, second reading,
vacating Frank and a small segment of a
previously vacated alley north of Rock
Springs Street, City of Cheyenne,
Laramie County, Wyoming, located east of
North College Drive and north of Rock
Springs Street.
>> Uh, do we have a staff report,
Mr. White?
Chair and members of the committee,
Conor White Planning and Development
Department.
So, this is a street vacation. It's for
a portion of what is known as Frank
Court. It's north of Rock Springs. Uh
there is a small portion of an alley in
here as well with the vacation.
This is a city initiated vacation. Um if
you remember, we had a preliminary plat
that came before council. believe it was
back in January where one of the
conditions uh for that preliminary plat
was that the applicant provide city
staff a vacation map and the city would
initiate the vacation as they did not
have all owners um basically that are
adjacent to the street sign off to
basically be able to vacate that with a
platting action. So the city's the one
vacating the street. Um right now this
is an unbuilt street that the city is
required to maintain. Um the north half
of the or yeah the north part of the
street um half of it is actually
currently being used as the house that's
at the end of the street. Uh they do
have a shed out in the rightway
currently. Again the only um the street
isn't built and there's really only two
property owners that use it. Um, the two
property owners that use it would be the
one that's located at the end, which was
a county pocket that we annexed. And
then the southwest corner, there's a
property owner there that they use it
for access to their garage.
With this vacation, um, basically half
the street that's adjacent to any of
these parcels goes to those property
owners and becomes their property. Um,
there are easements also provided within
this vacation to provide access. So on
the east side, it would provide access
to that lot that's at the end of the
street. And then there's also um still
working with BOPU to make sure we've got
the finalized easement on the south end
for the water and sewer main stubs that
uh go into Frank Court as those still
are existing stubs and if they're not
removed, we need to have that BOP
easement.
So still working on getting the exact
easement. Um so I may have a substitute
in the next week or two just with the
map.
Um so that we have that finalized
easement. Um
there is a final plat that will come
forward later on uh for the parcels on
the east that would then incorporate the
vacated rightaway. The additional
rightaway that's being vacated on the
west side would just remain as basically
their own parcels, but would go to the
property owners adjacent.
Planning commission did hear this at
this at their March 2nd uh planning
commission meeting and they did
recommend approval. The only public
comment I've had on this is actually
from the property owner to the
southwest. Uh he was just basically he
emailed me and was wondering making sure
that he still had access to his garage.
I did inform him that yes, he will still
have access as he will own 30 feet of
that right ofway. So, he will still have
that access uh to be able to get into
his garage. Other than that, there's
been no other public comment uh for this
uh project. I am available for any
questions. Okay.
>> Questions for Mr. White?
>> Chairwoman Nmanu. Um, when we do this
type of a vacation that's initiated by
the city, are we making sure that the
property owners understand that they
will become the ones responsible for the
maintenance from this point forward?
>> Madam Chair, through you, yes, that is
in I mean within our letters, we do
state that they become the owners. Um,
as well as
basically it's no longer a road. It
basically becomes their property. Um, so
it will show up on their taxes. It will
show up basically as them having
ownership and no longer a public
rightway. So that even right there will
show that the city no longer maintains
it as it's not public right away any
longer.
>> Thank you.
>> Any other questions for Mr. White?
Okay. Thank you. Is there any public
comment?
Okay.
Committee, what questions or thoughts do
you have?
>> Okay.
>> Yep.
>> I would move to approve on second and
final reading.
>> Okay. Dr. Aldridge moved and uh
Councilman Lebornne seconded.
>> All those in favor, please signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> And those.
Okay. So, the recommendation on Monday
night will be to approve on second
reading. With that, it's we've met all
of our responsibilities and we're done.
Thank you.